Karan Sota

Sr. iOS Developer at Apple Inc.

Summary

I am passionate about developing apps for iOS/Android and posses experience working with apps that are in hands of millions of users across the globe. I have worked on apps like OnStar RemoteLink, TrueCar Consumer Buy, Call of Duty Ghosts Companion, Call of Duty Advanced Warfare Companion, Call of Duty Black Ops II Companion, etc.

Experience

Sr. iOS Developer at Apple

June 2015 - Present

Sr. iOS / Android Developer at TrueCar, Inc.

April 2014 - June 2015 (1 year 2 months)

- Develop TrueCar Mobile Development Kit (MDK/SDK) to Support Partner Apps (USAA) on iOS/Android.
- Implement new features on iOS first and then port them on to Android.
- Also, building a lot of re-usable components for each platforms.
- Working extensively with RestFul API's.
- Implement unit testable code using strict MVC design pattern and write XCTests.
- Using the best development practices by following TDD, Git-flow, Pull Requests for Code Reviews, Continuous Integration using Jenkins, Pull Request Builder on Jenkins, building re-usable utility / UI classes.

iOS Developer at Activision Publishing Inc.

March 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 1 month)

- Implemented Dynamic App Configuration settings for API endpoints, localization strings and notifications.
- Implemented custom Style Manager that does CSS styling of the whole app based off of JSON.
- Built 100% Custom UI using Core Graphics.
- Implemented Second Screen: Connecting to console (live) while in-game for selecting load outs pre-match, in-match and also showing match results post match.
- Implemented pure MVC based architecture.
- Implemented MOCK services using Apiary, which provides JSON data.
- Implemented generic interfaces for API Get, Post, and Put & Delete Requests.
- Integrated Social Framework for Facebook & Twitter sharing.
- Fixed multiple bugs on legacy app.
- Worked closely with Design team for Design requirements and reviews.
- Worked closely with QA Automation Engineer for integrating UI automation and continuous integration.
- Worked closely with Managing Producer for Sprint Planning and requirements gathering.

iOS Developer at General Motors Company / OnStar, LLC

March 2012 - February 2013 (11 months)

- #- Converted iPhone code base to a Universal code base for supporting iPad.
- #Converted non-ARC project to ARC project.
- Implemented UI Automation and followed Test Driven Development (TDD) on possible stories with unit testing
- Perform tests on actual vehicle in the OnStar Laboratory.
- Scaled the app to support for iPhone 5 resolution.
- Implemented Nuance Voice Recognition API to execute remote commands with speech.
- Participate in Scrum meeting (daily) and Iteration Planning Meetings (bi-monthly).
- Participated in two OnStar Hackathon's to promote new ideas.
- Work closely with the Business Analyst and the other two huge teams (Android & HTML5) to discuss architecture & design.
- Manage the Apple developer and the enterprise account including code signing the app with enterprise profile.
- Work closely with the QA to perform and document the tests correctly.
- Work closely with the Web Services team to understand the API implementation to support new features.
- Work closely with the Graphics Designer in prototyping and discussing the design requirements.
- Participated in Book club on Agile Software Craftsmanship with team members and project manager.

Education

State University of New York at Binghamton

Master's degree, Computer Science, December 2012

Mumbai University

Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Karan Sota

Sr. iOS Developer at Apple Inc.



Contact Karan on LinkedIn